Guide to the Stanford University, Public Policy Program, honors theses SC4-6533
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Public Policy Program, honors theses
1988-2011
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University. Public Policy Program
SC4-6533
1.75 Linear Feet (36 volumes in 4 boxes)
Honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Public Policy Program.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of honors theses written by undergraduates in the Stanford University Public Policy Program.
Access to Collection
The collection is open for research use; materials must be requested at least 48 hours in advance of intended use. No photocopies may be made.
Acquisition Information
Theses were transferred to the Stanford University Archives from the Hume Writing Center in 2011.
Student papers.; Public policy; Stanford University. Public Policy Program
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2011-152
  - Carney, Stacie, The effects of managed care incentives on the urgency of emergency department visits., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Cline, David, An inherent relationship? The impact of Proposition 13 on the county,city, and city school district of San Mateo., 1989 (Box 1)
  - Cordova, Matthew A., Cooperative security as a framework for U.S. national security policy., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Flaherty, Colleen N., Determinants of the decision to annuitize defined contribution plan balances: a study of individuals retired between 1995 and 2000., 2002 (Box 1)
  - Gilbert, Julie R,, The impact of health care reform on medical education: an organizational approach to the specialist-generalist debate., 1994 (Box 1)
  - Johnson, Julie A., Medicare medical savings accounts: winners, losers, and savings distributions., 1998 (Box 1)
  - Lurie, Steven, Black, white, and gold: the political involvement of domestic South African business during the Botha administration, 1978 - present., 1988 (Box 1)
  - Carney, Stacie, The effects of managed care incentives on the urgency of emergency department visits., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Chang, Emily Nailen, Serrano v. Priest, twenty years later: an empirical analysis of its effects on California school finance., 1997 (Box 1)
  - Cho, Sung-Woo, The economics of population migration: a study of African-American workers in 1950s America., 2004 (Box 1)
  - Bravo, Noel, Chicano voting rights: the continuing quest for full enfranchisement., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Garrison, Stephen, A Lone Star success? An evaluation of the shift of Texas Medicaid clients to managed care., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Kao, Daniel, Does hospital ownership structure influence staffing levels?., 1998 (Box 2)
  - Clark, Jill, Family processes associated with outstanding achivement in math and science by high school seniors., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Heimert, Andrew, The transportation pork barrel: the distribution of discretionary highway projects, 1984-1993. (Box 2)
  - Krim, Lisa, The glass ceiling: it's not clear nor easy to break the problem and policy solutions., 1991 (Box 2)
  - Mickelsen, Brady D., The arena: a theoretical analysis of Nixonian foreign policy., 1996 (Box 2)
  - Keller, Joshua R., Creating institutions: NAFTA and the North American Commission on the Environment., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Kohn, Amy, Persian Gulf legislation: its impact on the VA health care system., 1995 (Box 2)
  - Alter, Alison Beth, European structural policy: the case of italy in micro perspective., 1993 (Box 2)
  - Khalessi, Arash Alexander, The role of foreign assistance in permanent health sector development: health-for-all and the Kenyan experience., 1999 (Box 2)
  - Stichler, Keith, Regenerating cities through public-private partnerships: a comparison of the United States and Britain., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Hinrichs, Susan, Prevention among teenagers: an examination of contraceptive use to evaluate the feasibility of coordinating AIDS and pregnancy prevention policies., 1994 (Box 2)
  - Lerner, Carlos, The income distribution of government health care benefits., 1992 (Box 2)
  - Mittal, Rashi, ASEAN Monetary Union -- a possibility? A comparison of ASEAN economic indicators with that of the Euro Zone., 2004 (Box 3)
  - Dubé, Oeindrila, Globalization, outsourcing and union power., 2000 (Box 3)
  - Pompa, Laurie Marie, Motherhood: exploring the economic implications for women., 2004 (Box 3)
  - Thomas, David A., Moving welfare recipients to work: trends in the general assistance population of San Mateo County, California, 1993-1997., 1998 (Box 3)
  - Oram, Jon H., Efficient resource allocation by the U.S. Senate: Title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act., 1996 (Box 3)
  - Chang, Ailsa, Wrestling out of the legal headlock: a philosophical reexamination and defense of university hate speech codes., 1998 (Box 3)
  - Jewett, Michelle, Stability in income inequality in the former German Democratic Republic following reunification., 1999 (Box 3)
  - Ho, James C., Solving the Medicare crisis: the need for radical reform., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Nash, Christine A., Turning the school inside out: learning within the school and beyond., 1994 (Box 3)
  - Liu, Shan Woo, Implementing school AIDS education: an analysis of the barriers facing the Honduran Ministries of Health and Education., 1995 (Box 3)
  - Jimmerson, LaKesha, How does a hospital's not-for-profit or for-profit status affect its commitment to community?., 2002 (Box 3)
- Theses, Accession ARCH-2018-060
  - Marks, Miriam Ellora, "The hazards posed by and determinants of delayed male marriage in Egypt", 2011 May 18 (Box 1)